# Sonja Parsell

NYC Metro Area | 203-321-9889 | hello@sparsell.com | www.sparsell.com | GitHub| LinkedIn

#### **PROFILE**

I'm an organized, detail-oriented and curious software engineer with experience designing and building modern web applications in React, JavaScript and Rails. I spent nearly 15 years working in financial services with experience in P/L production, project management, global collaboration, and team management and building, across all financial asset classes. I'm highly resourceful, and relentlessly pursue efficiency and accuracy.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, HTML5, CSS, ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Git, GitHub, JSON, RESTful routes, MVC design patterns, JIRA, Sharepoint

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## ClassTech - GITHUB

React | Redux | Rails (API) | PostgreSQL

- App for parents to show their kids which classmates have their own phone.
- User can add a new student and view all students by grade, noting their phone status and any screen time limits they might have. Heavy interest amongst parent groups for this to be live; hosting in progress.

#### SpendLess - GITHUB

JavaScript | Rails (API) | SQLite

- App to record when a user has spent "less"; proves how small changes to your spending mindset can save money.
- User can set a goal, add amounts, and view a cumulative total of how much they have saved, or, "spent less".

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### The Collab Lab

**Barclays Capital** 

Software Engineering Apprentice

April 2022 - Present

## Volunteer - Leukemia and Lymphoma Society

Volunteer - Salesforce Administrator - Maintain patient outreach data and special projects

New York Metro Area 08/2019 - Present

**Volunteer - Whitby School** 

Greenwich, CT 08/2017 - 08/2019

School Board Member - Fundraising Chair (2016) - Raised over \$450k at annual gala

New York, NY and London, UK

Vice President - IT Service Delivery Manager, Prime Brokerage Controller

08/2008 - 02/2013

- Reduced delivery time of daily exceptions report by 6 hours by aligning production teams globally
- Continuously analyzed business requirements; liaised between business and development teams

Vice President - Prime Services Product Controller

- Redesigned daily P/L production process for Asia Desk by collaborating with local teams
- Created and implemented control review program for Prime Brokerage

JPMorgan Chase New York, NY

Vice President - Structured Notes Controller, Corporate Trust Relationship Manager

03/2003 - 08/2008

- Increased accuracy of revenue allocation by 43%; appointed as project lead for division roll-out
- Recovered \$250k from client billing errors after self-initiated analysis and discovery of hard-coded software
- Established revenue share procedures across divisional sales teams and all asset classes

Deutsche Bank

New York, NY and London, UK

Assistant Vice President - Client Relationship Manager - Corporate Trust / Project Finance / Escrow 02/1998 - 11/2002

- Led project and was primary testing resource to move collateral management system to proprietary software
- Increased client revenue by 18% through excellent client relationships and referrals

#### **EDUCATION**

The Frankfurt School Blockchain Center - DLT Talents - Cohort #4 Flatiron School, Full Stack Web Development - Software Engineering Pepperdine University, Malibu, CA: BS, Business, BA, French

4/2022 - Present

03/2020 - 11/2021

07/1995